# **BENJAMIN TAN**

# Blockchain Developer

benjamin@prohub.work https://github.com/CodeMaestro11

#### PROFIL F

I'm a Blockchain Developer with over 8 years of industry experience. Graduated from Toronto Metropolitan University with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and have been deeply involved in Experience ranges from writing smart contracts to creating decentralized apps, with a particular focus on the Ethereum and Solana platforms.

Main toolkit includes programming with Solidity, Rust, and React.js, along with expertise in Web3 technologies.

As I have collaborated to integrate blockchain capabilities into large-scale applications, teamwork is at the core of my approach.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE

08/2012 - 07/2016 SINGAPORE

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Blockchain Developer

10/2019 - 02/2024

#### **PixelPlex**

remote United States

PixelPlex helps you turn your ideas into market-ready software solutions, no matter how challenging they are.

- Developed and implemented smart contracts for KicklCO, an Ethereumbased crowdfunding platform, using Solidity.
- Led the creation of an ICO smart contract generator, streamlining the process for campaign founders.
- Collaborated closely with backend and frontend teams to ensure seamless integration of blockchain-powered features.
- Contributed to KicklCO's success by enabling groundbreaking startup projects to raise funds securely through token sales.

#### Junior Blockchain Developer

08/2016 - 09/2019

# PixelPlex

remote United States

- Developed the Allotment Alf protocol within the Alfprotocol ecosystem on the Solana blockchain.
- Designed and coded smart contracts for lending and overcollateralized borrowing, enhancing liquidity provision.
- Ensured seamless integration with existing protocols and maintained interoperability within the platform.
- Contributed to PixelPlex's expertise in blockchain technology and DeFi solutions through meticulous attention to detail and collaboration with the project team.



#### **SKILLS**

Bitcoin · Ethereum · Solana ·

Hardhat · Truffle · Foundry · L2 ·

ZK · Cryptography · Defi · DEX ·

DAO · NFT · Smart Contract ·

Solidity · Rust · Anchor ·

TypeScript · UI/UX design · SCSS ·

LESS · React.js · Vue · Angular ·

C++ · C# · Mocha · Chai · IPFS ·

Polkadot · Data-structure ·

 $Algorithm \cdot Next.js \cdot Nuxt.js \cdot$ 

SOLID · CI/CD · Git · Github · AWS ·

GCP · Azure · NGINX · Apache ·

Docker · Kubernetes · Ethers.js ·

Web3.js · Cosmos SDK

#### **LANGUAGES**

Tamil Native

English Proficient IIIII